<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installing a Web Server on Amazon CloudOps Linux Workshop</title>
    <link>/3.installing_a_webserver.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installing a Web Server on Amazon CloudOps Linux Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/3.installing_a_webserver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install Apache httpd</title>
      <link>/3.installing_a_webserver/install_httpd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3.installing_a_webserver/install_httpd.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the yum package manager to install a popular open-source web server, Apache httpd. Start connecting to the EC2 instance that you created earlier
Get the latest bug fixes and security updates by updating the software on your EC2 instance. To do this, use the following command: sudo is Superuser Do - this command allows normal users to run commands as root (the superuser). Installing software is one common task for the superuser (usually).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Content</title>
      <link>/3.installing_a_webserver/add_content.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3.installing_a_webserver/add_content.html</guid>
      <description>By default, Apache httpd stores web content in the /var/www directory. To allow the ec2-user user to manage files in the default root directory for your Apache web server, modify the ownership and permissions of the /var/www directory. In this tutorial, you add a group named www to your EC2 instance and add the ec2-user user as a member of that group. Then you give that group ownership of the /var/www directory and add write permissions for the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure the Network</title>
      <link>/3.installing_a_webserver/config_network.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/3.installing_a_webserver/config_network.html</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll have to open port 80 on the web server so that you can access it from the internet. We do this by configuring a security group rule on the AWS console.
 Click on your instance in the EC2 console. Then, select the Security tab in the window below. Click to open the Security Group. It should be named something like sg-0fed659811d69a592 (launch-wizard-81). In the Security Group console, click Edit Inbound Rules Click Add Rule Add a rule for Port Range = 80 and Source = My IP Click Save Rules  You can now test that your web server is properly installed and started.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
